Toheeb Adedokun

A proactive, smart, driven engineer and leader with 3years of development experience. I have developed software solutions for business use cases from conceptualization to deployment. A Full-stack JavaScript engineer, eager to contribute to team success through efficient work, attention to detail, and excellent communication skills. Software I have built includes Job Finder App, E-commerce App , IT-Service Web App and a lot of other projects. I currently work with the MERN Stack.

7, Asajon Way, Sangotedo Lagos State, Nigeria, NG. +2348138349465 Email:adedokuntoyyib@gma il.com

EXPERIENCE

GPI Technologies, Lagos — Software Engineer

MAY 2022 - PRESENT

- A member of a team that seeks to remodel and build bank card personalization software for better user experience, interaction and management.
- Member of a team working on a marketplace project to initiate and conduct transactions between.
- Writing high-quality, scalable and maintainable code with test coverage.

Decagon, Lagos — Software Engineer

OCTOBER 2021 - MAY 2022

- A member of a team that developed Decablog/Microblog, where Decagon elite developers and other engineers are able to upload and blog on articles of related tech interest.
- A member of a team that built a wallet API for easy currency exchange between major currencies and also tracked users' expenditures using MERN Stack.
- A member of a team that built a mini e-commerce website to aid seamless trade within a particular location using MERN stack.
- A member of a team that built an IT service web application for a company-partner management system for various operations.
- Experience writing unit and integration tests.

Side Hustle Technologies, Lagos — Software Engineer

APRIL 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- A member of a team that built the pension scheme application for the Nigerian Police.
- Implemented a MongoDB transfer system API
- Incorporated the MongoDB transactions API to ensure that some database operations either succeed or fail.
- Handled scheduled tasks with MongoDB.
- Collaborated with software teams to alleviate and fix bugs and errors in the company's system
- Exposure to agile methodologies
- Built projects with Nodejs, React.js, and Typescript.
- Handled Database Management System with SQL like MySQL, Postgresql, or NoSQL databases like MongoDB.
- A member of a team that built the Housing Loan Scheme application for the Nigerian Police
- Collaborated with the company's mentor to learn software best practices
- Experience writing unit and integration test.

TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML 5
- CSS
- Tailwind CSS
- Javascript
- Typescript
- Node.js
- Express Framework
- GraphQL
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- MongoDB
- MySql
- Postgresql
- React.js
- React-Redux
- Context API
- React Hooks
- Agile Methodologies
- Heroku
- Version Control with Git and Github.
- Test-Driven
 Development.

QEA Solutions — Software Developer

JANUARY 2020 - APRIL 2021

- Collaborated with other developers and members of different teams to alleviate bugs in software designs
- A member of a team that developed a web-based fashion solution.
- Member of a tea that wrote technical documentation for new software in development.
- Managed state and HTTP requests with Axios and Redux.
- Experience writing unit and integration tests.
- Exposure to agile methodologies.
- Member of a team developing, architecting, and implementing backend APIs for Book library systems.
- Helped in updating/revamping existing API for better user experience and improved application performance.
- A member of a team that provided software solutions.
- Worked with front-end development tools.
- Directed software designs and implementations
- Advised clients on software management and maintenance
- Collaborated with other team members on software best practices
- Integral part of the team that built the API for emergency reporting mobile application for the Delta State Government.

PROJECTS

DECA JOB:

A job search web application project that allows different categories of users to search, post, update jobs and perform several other authorized functions. The job-seekers can search based on the job title, location, and company. They can also apply for jobs accordingly.

Technologies Used - Node.js, Typescript, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Docker, Heroku, React.js, React Hooks.

Link: http://decajob.netlify.app

APPOGA:

Appoga app is an IT services web application with a myriad of functionalities. The basic core features of the app include product and service management. There are sections to post articles, blogs, quotes, search and apply for jobs. On the Appoga app, you can register your organization to become a partner.

Technologies Used - Node.js, ExpressJs, Typescript, SCSS, MongoDB, Heroku, React.js, React Hooks.

Link: http://appoga.com

DECABLOG:

A Decagon blog project, where decagon developers and other engineers can blog and post related tech articles

Technologies Used - Node.js, Typescript, MongoDB, Docker, Heroku, React.js, React Hooks.

Link: http://deca-blog.netlify.app

E-Commerce Comfy Web App:

An e-commerce application for fashion where users can browse through different wears, add to cart, checkout, and make purchases.

Technologies Used: Node.js, Express Framework, Typescript, React,

React Hooks, MySql, Firebase, Stripe

Link: https://comfy-store-api.herokuapp.com/

Job Finder App:

A web app that has its functionality in helping job-seekers easily find their dream jobs for easy application at no cost. Both employers and job-seekers are able to manage their jobs in a befitting way.

Technologies Used: Node.js, ExpressJs, React.js, Typescript, MongoDB

Link: https://jobwebapps.herokuapp.com/

LINKS

Github: https://github.com/rxgoodness

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/toheeb-adedokun

EDUCATION

Obafemi Awolowo University — B.Pharm

MARCH 2013 - APRIL 2018

Bachelor of Pharmacy (Hons.).